Papers of Andrew L. Riker and Family
Bridgeport History Center, Bridgeport Public Library
- Series X: Clippings
  - Fairfield News, Editorial by A.L. Riker, 1930 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - 50 Years of Motor Cars, 1946 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - "The Antiquarian", 1950 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - New York Times Magazine, Photos of Riker electric, 1967 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - New York Times Magazine, Photos of Riker electric, 1967 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Antique Motor News, History of Locomobile, 1978 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Antique car clippings, undated (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Electric car clippings, undated (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Clippings, undated (Box 11, Folder 17-24)
- Series XI: Photographs
  - Photographs, Naval Consulting Board, New York City parade photos, undated (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Photographs, Naval Consulting Board, Visit to proving grounds, undated (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Photographs, electric car, 1897 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Photographs, The Riker screen, undated (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Photographs, Exhibit at the American Institute, 1892 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Photographs, Electric Surrey, 1897 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Photographs, Riker Electric at Harrah’s, 1896 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Photographs, first Riker Electric (bicycles), undated (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Photographs, Electric surrey, undated (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Photographs, Riker Electric Victoria, undated (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Photographs, Riker Electric vehicles, 1896-1897 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Photographs, Riker exhibit at Madison Square Garden, 1899 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Photographs, Riker Electric, undated (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Photographs, Riker Electric, unlabeled, includes negatives, 1889-1901 (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Photographs, auto show, undated (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Photographs, "waters" winder of Riker Electric Motor, negatives, 1888 (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - Riker electric plant and products, 1888-1890 (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - Photographs, negatives, undated (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - Photographs, Cars, 1880-1959 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Photographs, work areas, 1887-1890 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Photographs, individual car parts, 1897-1910 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Photographs, Riker Electric Motor exhibit, 1890 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Photographs, awards, 1900 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Photographs, exhibit of Priestman oil engine, undated (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Photograph album created by A.L. Riker, undated (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Sub-group B: Andrew L. Riker's personal life (Box *, Folder *)
- Series I: Life material
  - Cash journal for house in Newton, 1840-1850 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Letter, Andrew W. Riker to parents, 1898 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, A.L. Riker, 1930-1939 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Clippings, Wedding, 1880- 1889 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence A. L. Riker and family with Dewel Family, undated (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - School books belonging to Andrew L. Riker, 1876 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - "The Reveille" from Peekskill Military Academy, 1886 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Wedding invitation, 1900 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Material related to Pittsburg trip, 1903 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Program, "Dew Lockstepper’s Minstrels" featuring Edith Riker in the cast and an ad for Locomobile, 1913 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Program. "The College Hero" featuring Edith and Lawrence Riker in the cast for May 19-21, 1913 (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Program, "A Midsummer night’s dream" featuring Edith and Andrew L. Riker Jr. in cast and ad for Locomobile, 1913 (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Material relating to Riker owned yachts, undated (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Ocolaqua, parts list for engine, undated (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - Logbook for the Ocolaqua, 1910-1913 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - License for the Ocolaqua, 1917 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Ventilouve Yacht Information pack, 1920-1929 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Christmas card list, 1928-1929 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Art given to Riker by friends and children, undated (Box 15, Folder 5)
- Series II: Death, funeral, and estate, undated
  - Obit from Fairfield News, 1930 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Obituaries for A.L. Riker, 1930 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Telegrams of sympathy, 1930 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Letters of sympathy, 1930 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Resolution of sympathy from town of Fairfield, 1930 (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Carriage list and funeral invitations, undated (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Assessment of Riker estate, 1934 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Andrew L. Riker Report of Trustees of Estate, 1933-1934 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Riker Connecticut properties cash journal, 1934-1936 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Andrew L. Riker Estate, quitclaim "Whitegate" to children, undated (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Riker estate, homestead and tax settlements, undated (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Sub-collection B: Riker Family, undated
- Series I: Edith L. Riker
  - "Church and Town" a survey of life in Fairfield, 1888-1913 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Edith Riker, correspondence with J. Raynor Whiting (brother), 1899-1931 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Warehouse receipts, Lincoln Safe Deposit Company, 1894-1895 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Engagement books, Edith Riker, 1813 (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Automobile log book belonging to Edith, 1910-1919 (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Electrical Navigation transcribed by "E.R.", undated (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - Garden club, 1924-1926 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Story of the Annual Meetings of the Garden Club of America by Mrs ALR, 1924-1925 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Wills, 1930 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Edith L. Riker, Obituaries, 1933 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Edith L. Riker Estate, Executor’s report and other probate documents, 1934 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Genealogies of Riker and Whiting families, undated (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - A.L. Riker biography for Cooperative Press, 1915 (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Additional Riker info, undated (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Biographical materials relating to Riker and Riker family, undated (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - Andrew and Edith genealogy info, relating to Society of Mayflower Descendants, undated (Box 17, Folder 10)
- Series II: Andrew L. Riker Jr.
  - Correspondence, 1922-1979 (Box 18, Folder 1-3)
  - Records of Riker Real Estate, 1955 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Riker Realty Corporation, correspondence, 1935-1946 (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Speed change electrical signal patent applications and draft, 1933 (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Political materials from Andrew L. Riker Jr.'s campaign, 1940-1949 (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Veteran Motor Car Club meet, 1945 (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Antique car shows, books, services, museums, 1960-1969 (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - Automobile Quarterly, 1960-1969 (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - Veteran Motor Car Club of America, 1960-1979 (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - Antique Automobile Club of America membership roster, 1970 (Box 18, Folder 12)
  - Plaques for fall foliage tour, 1978 (Box 18, Folder 13)
  - Andrew L. Riker Jr. biography and obituaries, 1978 (Box 18, Folder 14)
  - Auction for contents of Riker home in Manchester, 1984 (Box 18, Folder 15)
  - "The Riker" transcript by Andrew L. Riker Jr., undated (Box 18, Folder 16)
  - "History of the Locomobile Company of America part 2" typescript by Andrew L. Riker Junior, undated (Box 18, Folder 17)
  - "History of the Locomobile Company of America part 3" typescript by Andrew L. Riker Junior, undated (Box 18, Folder 18)
  - Timeline scrapbook of life of Andrew L. Riker created by Andrew L. Riker Junior, undated (Box 18, Folder 19)
  - Research material, Riker Electric Motor Vehicle, undated (Box 18, Folder 20)
  - Scrapbook featuring Locomobile material created by Andrew L. Riker Junior, undated (Box 18, Folder 21)
  - List of material on Riker Electrics, 1966 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Research material on Locomobile, primary sources, undated (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - List of Locomobile owners, undated (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Races and lists of prizes, undated (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Research notes, various timelines, 1969 (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Research material, additional ephemera, undated (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Research notes, undated (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Research notes on index cards, undated (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Research correspondence, 1938-1979 (Box 19, Folder 9-11)
  - Research correspondence related to #16, 1940-1979 (Box 19, Folder 12)
  - Research cards relating to Locomobile used by A.L. Riker Junior, undated (Box 20-21)
- Series III: Eleanor Riker
  - Eleanor Riker, correspondence, undated (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Eleanor Riker, clippings and ephemera, undated (Box 22, Folder 2)
- Series IV: Extended Riker family
  - Correspondence to Richard Lawrence, 1844 (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Minute book and Correspondence for the Volunteer Patriots Fund of Newton, L.I., 1861 (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Diary, Lettie L. Riker, 1865 (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Memoir and death of Gertrude Whiting (mother of Edith Riker nee Whiting), 1881-1884 (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Summer home of Jonathan L. Riker and William J. Riker, 1901 (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - William J. Riker baptismal certificate, 1905 (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - John L. Riker obituary, 1909 (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Charlotte L. Riker, will copy, 1913 (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Will of Mary Hayden mentioning A. L. Riker, undated (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - Autograph book belonging to Edith Whiting, undated (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - Richard W. Riker composition book, undated (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - Richard W. Riker personal files, undated (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - Riker estate, 1928-1949 (Box 23, Folder 9)
  - Riker genealogy, 1918 (Box 23, Folder 10)
  - Additional manuscript materials from other family members, 1888-1945 (Box 23, Folder 11)
- Series V: Photographs
  - Photographs, formal photo of A.L. Riker, 1890-1899 (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - Photographs, A.L. Riker, undated (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - Photographs, Riker and his children, 1880-1900 (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - Photographs, school photographs, unclear if A.L. Riker or A.L. Riker Junior, undated (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - Photographs, A.L. Riker Junior in Navy, undated (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - Photographs, formal portraits of A.L. Riker Junior, undated (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - Photographs, Billy Riker, undated (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - Photographs, Charlotte and Edith Riker, undated (Box 24, Folder 8)
  - Photographs, Edith W. Riker, undated (Box 24, Folder 9)
  - Frances L. Riker, A. Schuyler Clark Jr., Biki Riker, 1909 (Box 24, Folder 10)
  - Jane Margaret Riker, undated (Box 24, Folder 11)
  - Photographs, John L. Riker and wife, undated (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Photographs, Larry Riker, undated (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Photographs, Lavinia Smith Riker, undated (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - Photographs, Margaret Riker, undated (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Photographs, Mary Riker, undated (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Photographs, Ruth and Julia Riker, undated (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - Photographs, Samuel Riker, undated (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - Photographs, William J. Riker Junior, undated (Box 25, Folder 8)
  - Photographs, Riker family group photos, undated (Box 25, Folder 9-10)
  - Ditmars family, undated (Box 25, Folder 11)
  - Sylvannus and Helen Smith, undated (Box 25, Folder 12)
  - Mary Annna Styker with Rikers, undated (Box 25, Folder 13)
  - Maragaret Lawrence Strong, undated (Box 25, Folder 14)
  - Unknown Riker family members, undated (Box 25, Folder 15-16)
  - Photographs, Riker estate, undated (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Photographs, Hayden property, undated (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - Photographs, other holdings, undated (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - Photographs, The Ocolaqua, undated (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - Photographs, The Ocolaqua and others, undated (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - Photographs, The Ocolaqua and others on stiff backing, undated (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - Photographs, St Augustine and Daytona, undated (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - Photographs, Riker family vacation in St. Augustine and Daytona, Florida, undated (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - Photographs, Riker family vacations, undated (Box 27, Folder 2-4)
  - Photographs, Boston, undated (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - Photographs, churches, undated (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - Photographs, camping, undated (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - Photo documentation, undated (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - Prints from stereoptic slides, 1890-1899 (Box 28, Folder 5)
  - Photographs, unidentified, undated (Box 28, Folder 6)
  - Negatives, St. Augustine and Dayton, undated (Box 28, Folder 7)
  - Negatives, Riker family travels, undated (Box 28, Folder 8)
  - Prints and negatives from stereoptic slides, vacation images, 1890-1899 (Box 28, Folder 9)
  - Negatives, slide film, undated (Box 28, Folder 10)
  - Riker Stereopticon slides, undated (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - Riker family negatives in need of conservation, undated (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - Riker family negatives in need of conservation, undated (Box 31, Folder 1)
- Sub-group C: Oversize
  - Razor strap belonging to Andrew L. Riker, undated (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - Schematics, undated (Box 33, Folder 1)
  - Scrapbook, 1915 (Box 34, Folder 1)
  - Clippings scrapbook, 1910-1930s, loose pages, 1910-1939 (Box 35, Folder 1)
  - Clippings scrapbook, 1910-1930s, loose pages, 1910-1939 (Box 36, Folder 1)
  - Rolled up materials that require conservation, unavailable, undated (Box 37, Folder 1)